### ANUPAM MALLICK

Mail: anup88.2010@gmail.com / anup88.2010@yahoo.com

Phone: +91 9732462897 / +91 6297444060

Linkedin: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/anupam-mallick-83a3b1120">https://www.linkedin.com/in/anupam-mallick-83a3b1120</a>

### **Career Objective**

In quest of assignments in the technical areas where I can maximize my technical skills, program development, and training experience. Experienced Web Developer with a total experience of 9 years plus. Currently Working as Web Developer in Angular, Javascript, JQuery, Ajax, PHP, Laravel, MySQL,MongoDB, Ionic, Wordpress, React js, Typescript, and git.

### **Skills**

|             | HTML, CSS, Angular, JavaScript, JQuery, AJAX, TypeScript, PHP, Laravel, MySQL, MongoDB, Ionic, Restful API, WordPress, Shopify, React(basic) |
|-------------|--|
| 1 oois Useu | Git<br>Bitbucket<br>POSTMAN  |
| Domain      | Retail, Ecommerce, Education, Health Care.   |

# **Education & Learning Education**

| Qualification                             | University/Board              | Year Of Pass | Percentage/Grade |
|---|-------------------------------|--------------|------------------|
| Bachelor of Computer<br>Application (BCA) | Netaji Subhas Open University | 2010-2011    | 65               |
| Higher Secondary Examination              | W.B.C.H.S.E.                  | 2007         | 36.6             |
| Secondary Examination                     | W.B.B.S.E.                    | 2004         | 50.25            |

## **Work Experience**

| Organization Name | MESD Technology  |  |
|-------------------|--|--|
| Duration          | 2.4 years  |  |
| Period            | 05/04/2021 - 09/08/2023  |  |
| Roles             | Web Developer  |  |
| Location          | Pandua, Hooghly, India   |  |
| Responsibility    | <ul> <li>Work with development teams and product managers to ideate application and website.</li> <li>Design client-side and server-side architecture.</li> <li>Build the front-end of applications through appealing visual design.</li> <li>Switch between front-end development and back-end development as required.</li> <li>Write effective APIs.</li> <li>Troubleshoot, debug and upgrade application and website.</li> <li>Test software to ensure responsiveness and efficiency.</li> <li>Build features and applications with a mobile responsive design.</li> </ul> |  |
| Technical Skills  | HTML, CSS, Angular, Javascript, Jquery, AJAX, PHP, Laravel, MySql, Ionic, React, Ionic, WordPress.   |  |
| Tools             | Postman, Git, Bitbucket  |  |

| Organization Name | MS WEB DESIGNER (Shopify Experts)  |
|-------------------|--|
| Duration          | 10 months  |
| Period            | 08/03/2019 – 29/01/2020  |
| Roles             | Senior Developer   |
| Location          | Salt Lake Sector-v, Kolkata, India   |
| Responsibility    | <ul> <li>Responsible for the development of the Shopify platform, themes, liquid programming.</li> <li>Develop custom-tailored Shopify themes for Shopify plus clients.</li> <li>Exposure to application development and extending Shopify functionalities using storefront APIs.</li> <li>Design UX based from our brand standard and style guide with customize new Shopify theme.</li> <li>Proficiency in working with various Shopify JS APIs (storefront, AJAX Cart, Sections, etc.).</li> <li>Implement system integrations that are crucial to our success.</li> <li>Implement advanced debugging techniques and usage of browser developer tools.</li> </ul> |
| Technical Skills  | Shopify, Javascript, Jquery, AJAX, Restful API, HTML, CSS  |
| Tools             | Git, Postman   |

| Organization Name | Colorgraphicz   |
|-------------------|---|
| Duration          | 5 months  |
| Period            | 01/08/2018 - 31/01/2019   |
| Roles             | Web Developer   |
| Location          | Dumdum, Kolkata, India  |
| Responsibility    | <ul> <li>Conducting analysis of website and application requirements.</li> <li>Writing back-end, front-end code and building efficient PHP modules.</li> <li>Developing back-end portals with an optimized database.</li> <li>Troubleshooting application and code issues.</li> <li>Updating and altering application features to enhance performance.</li> <li>Collaborating with clients to design websites and their functions.</li> <li>Generating and customize WordPress themes and plugins.</li> </ul> |
| Technical Skills  | HTML, CSS, PHP, Mysql, Javascript, jaqury, ajax, Angular, wordpress   |

| Organization Name | Frame Visual Production  |
|-------------------|--|
| Duration          | 2.3 years  |
| Period            | 13/04/2016 – 27/07/2018  |
| Roles             | Web Developer  |
| Location          | Naihati, North 24 Parganas, India  |
| Responsibility    | <ul> <li>Collaborating with clients to design websites and their functions.</li> <li>Developing the front-end of the website.</li> <li>Planning and creating the website architecture.</li> <li>Managing back-end tasks like database and server integration.</li> <li>Generating WordPress themes and plugins.</li> <li>Testing and troubleshooting the website.</li> <li>Analyzing live website performance.</li> <li>Maintaining website security and compliance.</li> <li>Researching technical specifications of a project based on client inputs.</li> <li>Ensuring the overall quality of a project.</li> </ul> |
| Technical Skills  | HTML, CSS, PHP, Mysql, Javascript, jaqury, ajax, WebRTC(Node.js) wordpress   |

| Organization Name | A.C.INFOTECH  |
|-------------------|---|
| Duration          | 2 years   |
| Period            | 04/04/2014 - 31/03/2016   |
| Roles             | Web Developer   |
| Location          | Konnagar, Hooghly, India  |
| Responsibility    | <ul> <li>Write "clean", well-designed code.</li> <li>Produce detailed specifications.</li> <li>Troubleshoot, test and maintain the core product software and databases to ensure strong optimization and functionality.</li> <li>Contribute in all phases of the development lifecycle.</li> <li>Follow industry best practices.</li> <li>Develop and deploy new features to facilitate related procedures and tools if necessary.</li> </ul> |
| Technical Skills  | HTML, CSS, PHP, Mysql, Javascript, jaqury, ajax, Angularjs, wordpress   |

| Organization Name | CHAKRABORTY CONSULTANCY SERVICES PVT.LTD   |
|-------------------|--|
| Duration          | 2.6 years  |
| Period            | 06/10/2011 - 28/02/2014  |
| Roles             | Trainee Engineer   |
| Location          | Konnagar, Hooghly, India   |
| Responsibility    | <ul> <li>Participate in requirements analysis.</li> <li>Collaborate with internal teams to produce software design and architecture.</li> <li>Write clean, scalable code using .NET programming languages.</li> <li>Test and deploy applications and systems.</li> <li>Revise, update, refactor and debug code.</li> <li>Improve existing software.</li> </ul> |
| Technical Skills  | VB.net, C#, SQL  |

## **Personal Details**

| Date of Birth     | 2 <sup>nd</sup> March 1988   |
|-------------------|--|
| Nationality       | Indian   |
| Sex               | Male   |
| Marital Status    | Single   |
| Father Name       | Nepal Mallick  |
| Permanent Address | Vill - Patra, P.O - Vitasen, P.S - Pandua, dist- Hooghly, Pin- 712149. |
| Hobbies           | Reading Magazines, Listening to music, Interaction with new peoples.   |
| Language Known    | English, Hindi & Bengali.  |